utan!?Kirito...
!?
Kirito...
You cannot fight, but I can.
Do not worry.
I shall rescue them and come right back.
I promise.
Thank
you
so
much for watching.
Thank you.
Why don't they flee
south where it is clear?
Amayori, wait here.
Should the enemy breach our defenses,
you must hold them back. You hear that?
Stand your ground and keep
those things out of our village!
Alice?
Look.
They will surround you if you stay here.
Have everyone evacuate by the South
Road while you still have time.
Are you insane?
My mansion...
I mean, this village is our home!
It can be rebuilt.
But if you stay, you will
surely be slaughtered.
Which is more important, your
possessions or your lives?
We must stay because it is what
Zink, our man-at-arms, ordered.
We are the last line of defense.
In this situation, everyone
must do what he says.
Even I, the village elder.
Imperial law is clear on that.
We should do as my sister says.
Please, father.
Sugou.
Listen to her.
You know she speaks the truth.
Our lives are more important.
I know we have to follow
the laws of the land.
But even so...
If we stay, we die!
We can't abandon our homes!
You're just a child and you
should mind your tongue.
We will stay and protect the village.
I see now.
This is your doing, isn't it?
These things from the Dark Territory
wouldn't be here if not for you, Alice.
Years ago, when you were a child and
trespassed onto their land, you were tainted.
You're a witch.
She is in league with the monsters.
I am a knight, and I revoke
the man-at-arms order.
You will all evacuate the village
by the south road, at once.
Those of you bearing
weapons shall take the lead.
You cannot be a knight!
Not in this village!
There's no calling for them here!
You can handle a sword reasonably well,
but claiming to be a knight is outrageous.
What if a knight from Senator heard this?
My name is Alice.
I am one of the three
knights who oversee Senator.
An Integrity Knight of the
Church, Alice Synthesis 30.
You're an Integrity Knight?
Why didn't you tell me?
In truth, I was afraid to
The knighthood is both my duty
And my punishment I knew you
weren't a sinner Deep down,
I knew I always believed in you
I will do as the Lady Knight commands
We shall evacuate
all those bearing weapons
will lead the villagers to the
south gate at once as soon as
everyone is out evacuate to the
forest south of the clearing
i need help with the wounded
and the elderly right behind
you hey you over there follow us
keep them safe father selka and mother
everyone yes m 'lady be safe as well
be careful don't get yourself hurt
Amayori!
There's way too many. Fall back! Retreat!
Burn them!
It'll burn everything!
Alice has a dragon?
What are you doing here?
There is no time to explain.
Follow the others to safety.
Hurry up!
I'll kill ye and eat your guts, you moron!
From this moment on, I fight for
that which is important to me.
the lives of my sister and parents.
I fight for the sake of what Kirito
and Eugeo sacrificed everything for.
The people.
Thank you, Kirito.
I am all right now.
Though I may still falter,
my purpose is crystal clear.
I shall persevere for
the sake of our cause.
Halt!
My name is Alice.
As long as I live, the human
realm will not fall to you.
So be gone!
Return to your homeland now, or
you will die where you stand!
Enhance Armaments!
Forward, you stupid-yoon girl!
I work on the foot-harvester,
and your bone hurts!
Storm and churn!
My flowers!
Hear me!
The End Mountains separate our lands!
Dig through it if you will.
But as long as we knights exist,
you are not to set foot here again.
make your choice step forward and drown in
your blood or retreat
to your land of darkness
Don't cry.
I'll make you a new doll. Thanks.
Father wanted to come see you off, but
with the repairs, no. I understand.
One day, when I have fulfilled my duties,
I will return, not as a
knight, but as Alice Zuburg.
Perhaps then I shall be able to say,
I have come home, father.
I will return to this village someday.
And even if I fall in
battle, I know my heart will.
Let's go.
Where the hell is everyone?
Hiding, duh.
Locate them.
There you go.
The subcontroller.
I patched into the backup power.
The subcons up and running
and ready for action now.
You better pray Kirito wakes up again.
Because if he doesn't, I
swear I'll make you pay!
I know, I know.
I'm going to do everything I can
to bring him back. I promise.
Take it easy.
You will get him back.
But this isn't the way to do it.
Try to stay calm.
You're right.
I'm okay now.
Just overreacted there for a minute.
Reporting in.
The primary and secondary
bulkheads are sealed and secure.
Also, all non-combat personnel have
been evacuated to the bow block.
Good work.
About how long will the bulkheads hold?
Depends.
If they have saws, eight hours.
A few minutes if they have explosives.
But they won't go with that.
Not on the primary, Bulkhead.
It's too close to the Light Cube Cluster.
All right.
Let's see where we stand.
Casualties first.
Please tell me everyone's okay.
They are, sir.
Three civvies with the research
team sustained minor injuries.
As for our SDF unit, it's suffered
two minor and two heavy injuries.
It's nothing life-threatening.
They're being treated now.
What about the ship?
Not so good, sir.
The bulkheads from the
bilge dock to main control
are offline and can't
be accessed remotely.
But the real issue is power.
The main line was cut, so
we're on auxiliary now.
The good news is we have stable
power all through the ship.
The bad news is we can't rotate the screw
props without rebooting the whole system.
Like a sea turtle without fins.
With a shark nipping at its belly
yes they got the bilge dock and all
12 sectors in the lower shaft the
bastards they got us good they did
all right they have main control
stl-1 and the nuclear reactor they
don't want to destroy us if they
did they would have blown us out of
the water by now.
The next question is, who
the hell are these people?
Higa, what do you think?
Oh, um, let's have a look-see.
Going by their suits and the hardware
they're packing, I'd say they were mercs.
And based on
their average size, I'm
pretty sure they're not Asian.
Well, look on the bright side.
At least For not being
attacked by our own special
forces which is a relief
we can also be sure of
one other thing whoever
these people are they know
about project alicization
yep you got that right
they broke in through the bilge deck and
headed straight for the main control room
they know about the stl
and they know we have
a true bottom-up ai they're here for alice
fortunately i locked main con
down in time i fixed it so
they can't interfere with the
simulation or eject alice's
fluctlight from the light
cube cluster that's fantastic
but then neither can we no we
can't no one can eject alice's
light cube externally either
them in main or us in here but
that's a good thing i mean
it's pretty much a win for our
side they can't access the
cluster by computer and they won't
break through the wall because
they know they'll damage it
it's only a matter of time till the asahi
comes with backup then it's game over
for those dumb asses game over but we
still don't know if we're playing the game
we're getting played
huh we're here where's
the asahi waiting sir the fleet commanding
yokosuka ordered her to keep her distance
and stand by until further notice they
seem to think we've been taken hostage
and are sitting tight until the attackers
make their demands here's what i think
our guests have to have a back channel to
someone high up in the sdf and if i'm
right the asahi won't move in until alice's
light cube has been retrieved well now we
know we're not dealing
with terrorists here
This isn't good.
If these guys are what I think they
are, they'll have an expert with them.
Who might realize they can eject
the cube from inside the Underworld.
Since they have control of STL-1,
they can drop someone in and use the
Virtual Console to execute the command.
And if they do that, then what?
The target cube will be
extracted from the Light
Cube cluster in the
center of the main shaft.
Then, it'll be sent through an air tube
to a hatch in the selected control room.
The hatch for this room's over there.
The other's in main con.
With them.
Well, now that we know what they want,
we have to retrieve Alice's
Fluck Light before they do.
Right now, that's up to Kirito.
Once again, all our hopes
are riding on his shoulders.
Higa, how is he?
What's his status currently?
Well, the short version is,
he's stable now, but he's
on the edge of not good.
That death gun dude's toxin
damaged Kirito's neural network,
and that's not something
conventional treatment can help.
We thought the STL could stimulate
the growth of a new network,
so we blocked his memory and
dropped him into the Underworld.
But this time, his memory didn't get blocked,
probably because of the neural damage.
He woke up in there as
his real-world self,
and we didn't find out until he called us.
What?
Hang on a second.
What about time?
It's accelerated in the Underworld.
How much time has passed
in there since he dove in?
About two and a half years.
For that whole time,
he's been interacting with the artificial
Fluctlights like they were real people.
He also knew that once
the simulation ended,
his new friends and their
world would be erased.
That's why he went to the
console in the Central Cathedral,
since that was the only
way to get a hold of us.
Or rather, Keeks here.
I bet he was going to try to convince
you to spare them and their world.
He had to fight like hell
to get to that console,
but he made it, thanks to some friends.
I couldn't check the event log
during all the commotion here,
but his friends helped him in
the fight with Axiom Church.
Some didn't make it.
When he got through to us,
he was in mental distress,
blaming himself for the
death of his friends.
And by doing that, he ended up
attacking his own Fluctlight.
It was right about then when those
jackasses cut the power line.
That caused a short circuit,
and the surge from that caused
a spike in the STL's output.
As a result, Kirito's self-destructive
impulse was actualized.
Then, his ego was...
deactivated.
I don't get it.
His ego was deactivated?
I didn't know that was possible.
Have a look at the screen.
That's a Fluctlight.
Kirito's Fluctlight, to be precise.
And that black hole right there is
where a person's self-image should be.
The self-image?
The idea, concept, or
mental image of oneself?
Yep.
All of your decision-making passes through
a simple yes-no pathway
in your Fluctlight.
It asks whether you should
or shouldn't do something,
based on whatever situation you're in.
For example, Dr.
Kojiro, when you're at your fave beef bowl
place, you ever order a second helping?
No.
Even if in your mind you're like, damn,
this is good, I could eat another bowl.
Never.
And that's your self-image
pathway at work.
Decisions can't lead to actions
unless they go through those circuits.
In Kirito's case, his Fluctlight
is damaged in that one spot.
He can't process what happens around
him and he can't initiate an action.
All he can do, I think, is stuff
he remembers from repetition.
Eating, sleeping, stuff like that.
Right now, I don't think he knows
who he is or what he should do.
And he can't speak, so
he can't ask for help.
But that's just my theory.
I'm sorry.
It's so sad that it's
so sad that it's so sad.
I can't live alone alone.
I don't want anyone to love you?
I don't know how much I can do it.
It's your story.
It's my body.
It's my love.
My goal.
I'm not going to die.
Next time, the final test.